Hey, everybody.
I am super excited, and we're super excited to be having this live stream.
Just a quick thing.
First, oh, my God, I'm just too excited and too nervous.
So first of all, thank you, everyone who is tuning in today for the Tailoring for MetaHumans
webinar.
Just a quick thing.
This is the first ever webinar with both Chlo and Unreal, so really excited for all of us
to be here, to be doing this together, and actually, like, having somebody in the same
room as me, which is really great.
Just a quick thing for all of our viewers in the chat, don't forget the chat is there
for you guys to use, and we would love to know a little bit more about our people in
the chat, in the view, a little bit about yourselves, where you guys are in the world,
maybe what do you guys use, which programs, or what do you do, so we know a little bit
more about you, because you're going to get to know a whole lot about us.
And so today, we're going to be taking you guys through some of the videos and live discussions
detailing the processes of creating a MetaHuman, creating an outfit, and then animating and
rendering all of that in Unreal, so we're really excited to be bringing that to you
guys.
But let's kick it off with just some quick introductions.
My name is Ariel.
I work here at Chlo as a 3D designer, 3D apparel designer.
And just something kind of fun, facts about myself, the first video game I ever played
was the Zork text version.
If anybody got that, I'm going to be so impressed.
But for everybody else, a little bit about myself, I did design a dress that Taylor Swift
wore years ago, so that was kind of a really cool highlight of my career.
And then from there, I'm going to kick it off, Billy.
Hello.
My name is Billy, and I am a 3D artist working for Marvelous Designer.
And my fun fact is I used to work in architecture.
And that also brings up the question.
Like, how does that relate to cloth simulation?
But that's a question for another time.
So I will hand it off to Kami.
Thanks, Billy.
Hi.
I'm Kami.
I'm a senior technical artist here at Epic.
I've been in the film and gaming industry for about 20 years, focusing on metahumans
and character creation, lighting, and look dev.
So I'm excited to be here with this team.
Fun fact about me is when I'm not behind the desk, I actually like to get out and go hiking
and had the opportunity to go hike up to Everest Base Camp.
Wow.
All fundraising, actually, for cancer and leukemia.
So it's kind of a twofer there.
But yeah.
I'll hand it on back to Kami.
Show off, Kami.
I'm Kami, lead clothing artist at Epic Games.
I've been at Epic for about five years.
Before that, I was in feature animation, and before that, I was a designer in the fashion
industry.
I guess I have to do a fun fact, too.
When I was a kid, I was on a game show that you've probably never heard of.
Great.
I'm going to have to ask you what that game was later.
All right, guys.
So just reminder, we do have the chat that's active.
And if you want to put any questions that you guys think of during this whole series,
please feel free to put them in the chat.
We are going to try to answer as many as we possibly can at the end of today.
So fun.
We'll have a Q&A at the end.
Everybody loves that.
And then a little other something.
So during today's presentations, definitely pay attention because we have a really exciting
contest that's going to be coming up soon.
Not announced yet.
But you guys are getting a little preview.
And a lot of what we're going to be talking about today is going to be super useful in
the upcoming competition.
But let's before we get into all of these videos and demos that we're going to be doing,
let's start and show off some of our artwork that creators have used on Unreal.
They've used Clo.
Maybe they've used Marvelous Designer and MetaHuman to create this really cool art.
So Dan, if you would be so kind, our man behind the curtain, to kick off some of these images.
All right.
So our very first thing up, I thought this was really cool.
If anybody isn't familiar with these holo boxes, they're super cool.
They're life size.
And this was hosted at a combined Unreal, Epic, and Clo event held in London earlier
this year.
I wish I got to go, but I'm going to actually let Kim talk a little bit about this because
she actually was there.
And I'm kind of jealous.
Yeah, I actually got to go.
It was very cool.
I mean, the holo boxes themselves.
They're basically human sized.
And so being able to experience some of these assets moving in a way that's just human sized
is really, really cool.
As you can see in here, the event itself was really great.
Also sort of, yeah, the energy was really great.
Everyone was really excited.
They showed a lot of really cool stuff, some of which you're going to get to see here today.
But yeah, it was a really good time.
But then we have actually just some focus features of some of the artists.
If we could scroll to our next one, Dan.
So Ashno, I just want to say something I think is really cool about this is that these have
such unique avatars or, well, they're Unreal humans, basically.
And how really creative you can get with these because they're not, you know, your traditional,
you think of, I'm going to just make an avatar and I'm going to make them look like a normal
person.
These are really, really completely unique.
Yeah, they really push them.
There's a lot of personality there, which is cool.
It's just really cool to see such a unique style in the 3D environment like this just
really shows the creative side that you can actually put into working in the 3D environment.
Yeah, storytelling is really good in these examples.
Like I feel like I can tell what type of people these, well, yeah, what these people are.
Who these people are, where they're from, who knows.
Hey, Dan, can we have our second artist, please?
This one I think is kind of my personal favorite, mostly because of the amount of insane movement
you're getting in this with the flow and the dress and the beads and the shine on the head
dress.
And I don't know if anybody thinks back to like old video games where like everybody
basically wore a square, you know, square with outfit painted on top.
So just to see how far it's come from when I was a kid to honestly how far it's come
in the past, like five, six years is insane because these video games bring so much more
life in the outfit.
It brings so much more life to the game.
Yeah.
Anyone who's ever worked in cloth simulation can just look at all those like beads flying
out and just be extremely impressed because it looks really cool and that's very complicated.
Yeah.
I mean, the level of detail that Unreal is able to capture in these renders is just,
it's awesome.
I really want to know how they made the jewelry and the beads.
I'm not going to lie, I'm with you on that, Billy.
You should ask.
I know.
We should.
We should get them on a tutorial on how to do that.
All right.
Third person, please, Dan.
Oh, yeah.
There we go.
All right.
I'm going to promise I've tried so hard to try to say her name right or Kidea.
I think I got it right.
Oh, she makes some of the most beautiful and absolutely ethereal things I've ever seen.
So like the clothes that are coming out of Clow, but then going using a MetaHuman and
then being rendered in Unreal.
I'm quite literally blown away because I want to step into this scene with this character.
It really shows the power, you know, of bringing your clothes and your avatar into something
like Unreal, you know, where you can, you know, set up like so much atmosphere and rent,
you know, like it looks, it really kicks it up like several notches, which looks really
cool.
Yeah.
I mean, I also want to make sure the next image I believe we have also, you can just
really see the atmosphere.
The lighting, how it accentuates the clothing and really just makes it pop, especially the
complimentary colors here and just the mood and raking across the front of the actual
clothing.
You can see every movement, every ripple.
It's almost like it's moving, even though it's a still.
You might have seen, but this was the artist who created the feature artwork for this live
session and also she was in the holobox.
So absolutely bonkers like talented artist here.
And we have one more.
One more person.
So last but not least blocky and something I kind of want to say about this, which I
think is really cool is a lot of times when we're thinking, we're thinking club, we're
thinking unreal, we're thinking medic human and we're thinking marvelous designer, we're
thinking digital.
And while this artist did use stuff to make all these digital artwork, the movement, the
animations that are up on these massive screens.
So like super high quality also used clothes for the merchant design that was physically
sold.
So it's really showing how all of that can come really full circle and have all of these
different elements and all of these different use cases, which I just think is kind of amazing.
What a cool workflow.
Okay.
I need a breakdown.
I mean, it really just shows you the power of the cinematics and actually bringing your
clothing to life, to movement, not just the stills that you can create there.
It really just kind of gives that connection.
And then to be seen on live screen, like big screen like that, and it holds up.
That's pretty rad.
Yeah.
It always blows my mind when I see stuff on the like Times Square sized billboards.
You're like, whoa, whoa, hold on a second.
So I think looking at all these artists, and if you guys have questions about the artists,
feel free to put them in the chat or go definitely check them out on it.
And just last but not least, I almost forgot some still images, but like, this is really
cool because you get so much motion, cinematography kind of action, everything feels very lively
in these shots.
Yeah.
And I mean, I really love this one because it really showcases the metahuman, like that
face is, you know, right up in the center, you know, super realistic.
It looks really great.
It really sells the realism and, you know, character.
Like it's not just, you know, a generic face.
It's a really interesting face with a lot of character, which I think is really cool.
We're good.
We're good on these guys.
I hope you guys enjoyed seeing some of these artists.
I definitely recommend checking them out on their websites, their social media, because
we've literally showed you the smallest snippet of what these guys are all like.
Their capabilities are, which I just think is absolutely insane.
But without further ado, we're kind of really here to see some demos of these different
softwares in action and kick it off.
We are going to have Kim presenting some absolutely amazing.
Yeah.
So this first video is just going to be showing you how to create a Meta human and trying
to go a little bit beyond the basics in some cases and just show you some stuff that you
may want to know, especially as someone who's going to be used that Meta human to bring
it into Clo to create clothing around it.
So take it away.
Hey everyone.
So hi, I'm Kim from Epic games.
I'm going to show you how to create a Meta human.
But first I'm going to briefly talk about why you would want to use a Meta human.
First off, they're easy to create highly customizable and super high quality avatars, which is probably
why you're interested in them, but they also have a lot of other benefits that you might
want to be aware of.
They live natively in unreal engine, no friction, no bridging plugins, animation tools like
Meta human animator and real time webcam animations are right there.
They connect to the DCCs you're already using like Clo, Marvelous, Maya, Houdini, and fast,
Epic's marketplace has a growing ecosystem of assets built around them.
So now the first thing that we're going to do is we're going to make a Meta human.
So I'm going to make a Meta human folder in here.
Probably not necessary.
And I'm going to right click and go to here, Meta human, Meta human character, name it
whatever you want.
I'm going to double click on that, which will open up.
The Meta human creator.
So this is Meta human creator.
It gives us this generic looking character.
We can have a look at it.
There's a couple of things I'm just going to point out really quickly.
We can swap from topology to skin, clay, you know, just different texturing.
There's also different lighting scenarios, you can switch to the LODs and quality, et
cetera.
I'm going to switch this back to skin.
And then we're going to briefly look at some of the head stuff.
So there's a number of different modes.
There's blend where you can stretch faces and these are all the presets that it comes
with.
I'm going to go into layer, I'm going to choose three of these presets.
And then as you can see in the face, there's all these little dots.
When you click on a dot, depending on the positioning here of the three characters.
So let's see, Lorenzo looks like you've got kind of a bigger nose.
So if I zoom in a little bit.
Okay.
If I bring the position closer to Lorenzo, I'll get Lorenzo's nose.
If I go in between Lorenzo and Era, I'll get some sort of a mixture.
And so that's how blending works, except it's transformed.
And sort of similar except, you know, in terms of it, it uses all of the various dots, but
instead of blending in between them, you can just select a dot and actually move it around.
So right now we have symmetric on, you can turn it off if you want some kind of asymmetry.
You've got teeth and eyelashes, and this is where you can edit things like teeth.
You know, there's some sliders, you can change the length of the teeth, the variation.
Now you can see how it looks like with the mouth open and the mouth closed.
And eyelashes, which I guess is pretty self-explanatory.
In form, we will come back to.
And here's sculpt.
So sculpt, again, you can grab any particular point and you can sculpt the character.
Again, you can have symmetry on or off.
Okay.
And so this gives you some of these really fine tuned controls if you want to really
tweak how your character looks.
And here's a really cool thing is if you hold control, you can create a new point.
One last thing to note that you may find very important is the head scale.
And so this controls how big or small the head is.
In relation to the body.
And here, of course, is the reset button where you can reset everything to the default.
Now, if you don't really feel like sculpting your own face, you can absolutely feel free
to take advantage of our presets.
And so these all ship with MetaHuman Creator.
You can go through them and decide if there's any face in here that you like.
And of course, you can choose a face that you like.
And you just double click on it to select it.
Or you can choose the face that you like and then start making changes.
And again, here you go.
You can reset if you don't like what you did.
So once you have your face, you might want to have some hair.
So you can click on this hair and clothing.
And up here on the top is all the head hair.
Here's eyebrows.
Scroll down over here.
You can have eyelashes, facial hair, etc.
And you can choose any of these.
These all come with MetaHuman Creator.
It's as simple as double clicking to select them.
And now you have that hairstyle.
I also have a couple of grooms that I downloaded off of Zap.
These are a couple of the free downloads available.
Made by Epic.
I'll drag them in right now.
And now those two styles have been added and I can choose.
And I can select them.
In addition to face controls, there's also materials that you want to play with.
You can play with skin tone.
You can change the skin tone.
You can change the body texture, the face texture, freckles, all kinds of stuff.
You can change eye color.
Makeup, etc.
There's teeth and eyelashes again.
So it's all a bunch of stuff that you can absolutely play around with.
A lot of fun there.
Now that we've looked at the face, let's check out the body.
Now, the way that we edit the body is actually kind of similar in a lot of ways to the way that we edit the face.
In the same way, we have different bodies that we can...
We can blend between in blend mode.
In the same way that you can double-click any preset to get the whole body, you can do that.
Or to the whole face, you can do that also with the body.
So if there's a body in here that you want your character to have or that you feel is a good spot in place, you can go ahead and double-click that.
You can also download bodies from Fab or you can distribute them amongst each other.
Basically, any MetaHuman file can essentially be used as a preset.
And so you can load them right into here.
Just drag MetaHuman right into here and you can use it as a preset.
It's a great way to distribute bodies amongst each other.
And then we have model.
The way that MetaHuman works in very simple terms is that a lot of bodies and faces have been scanned and put into a database.
And the database draws from those shapes to create bodies and faces.
And what our body model tries to do is to create the most plausible body given whatever parameters you choose.
So here's our list of parameters that you can control for the body.
They're sort of broken up into two sections.
And so there's these global parameters, which include masculine, feminine, muscularity, fat, and height.
And then there's individual measurements.
So we're going to go over the global parameters first.
And so masculine and feminine, relatively self-explanatory.
And so as you can see when I'm changing this, all of the other sliders are changing underneath.
And also you can see that when I change this, this little pushpin icon turns white.
And what that means is that this parameter is now locked because I've chosen it.
So when I change another parameter, let's say muscularity, as you can see, this setting of masculine or feminine is locked.
And now that I've changed this one, this is locked as well.
And you can always unlock it.
And it'll pop back to what it again feels like.
It's the most plausible choice.
And now let's look at all of these measurement ones.
So these you can click here.
They're all in centimeters.
And type in whatever your value is.
A lot of these are sort of generally fashion-related measurements that you might take in a body.
And so, you know.
You can control specific shapes and sizes of bodies.
And as you select them, this line will come up.
You can also start from a preset.
If it's pretty close to what you want.
And then switch over.
And then you can fine-tune it if you're interested in doing that.
If you want a really specific body, you can use the one that we've been missing, which is the conform.
And this also goes for the face.
What you would do with conform is you would download a...
Download the medicament topology.
Because the topology does have to match.
And inside an external VCC, you would take your body.
And you would make that body have our topology.
There's a lot of tutorials on this.
And then you would bring that body, which has your shape and our topology in.
And so you drag both a head and a body SVX.
And now we have the body static mesh and the head static mesh.
And so we go to from template.
We're looking for the body mesh here.
We click body.
And we're looking for the head mesh.
Here.
And now we're going to conform it.
And what we should get when we click conform is we should get the sort of generic medicament.
Because that's the SVX that I brought in here.
Now I have to go to head to conform.
I want to open template.
If I want to conform to that.
So you can see there's other options.
But I'm just conforming with the whole head.
And we should get the generic head back.
So now that we've explored a lot of the creation options.
I'm just going to show you a few last things that are useful.
We've talked about presets a lot.
But we didn't click on this preset tab.
And so this preset has the same presets that we've been looking for.
But they are more full presets.
Including skin tone, grooms.
And they have what is called the default garments.
Which is just a t-shirt and shorts.
So we're going to click on one.
Etta is the one that we are going to be using.
So here's Etta.
So I'm going to go and I'm going to turn the garment off.
And we're going to get ready to export this medicament.
This metahuman for glow.
And so the first thing that we're going to do is.
We're going to download texture sources.
And we're going to create the full rig.
So this is going to take a little bit.
So now that we've downloaded the texture sources and created a rig.
We can go to assemble.
But quickly first I just want to show you that.
Now that you have a rig in.
You can watch your character move.
And now that we've got the rig in textures.
We can assemble.
So there's a few assembly options here.
It starts out on Cine.
Which is a high quality.
And there's other ones.
The one that we want is DCC export.
And all we're going to want to do is just click here.
And select a location to save it.
Type it in.
And hit assemble.
And that's it.
It will create DNA.
For you to bring into Clo.
I don't know about all of everybody else.
And all of our viewers.
But I kind of feel super inspired to like go ahead and build my own metahuman right about now.
I don't know if it will try to make it look like me.
That might be terrifying.
But maybe make it look like somebody really cool.
That I can start to use in my Clo projects.
But can I say the coolest thing I thought I saw.
I'm like I can look here.
I can actually look at you in person.
But it was the blog.
But it was the blending.
Because having you.
I always thought it was so cool.
I was like okay.
I can take this person's nose.
And these person's eyes.
And some cheekbones from here.
And like blend it into like the person that I want it to be.
So and I've checked out metahuman personally before.
But I did not know that feature was there.
And I was like okay.
Well that just kind of blew me out of the water.
So that was really cool personally.
For me to see happening live.
Also just how like seamless that happened.
You can also do that with something that you with a metahuman you created yourself.
Like that you.
So this is.
Or anything.
So you can blend your own models as well.
Okay.
So I'm going to go deep down that rabbit hole.
Oh my god.
Great.
Perfect for me.
I mean the best thing that I think came out recently with is the parametric body system.
Right.
Finally being able to customize and fit to what you want.
What you look like.
And then the fact that the clothing will now conform and go along with that.
Right.
So it took it from our standard presets to just really being able to customize.
And I don't think a lot of people get a chance to play with that.
And realize how much the clothing.
Can actually adjust and move.
Which I think in the long run helps you guys with designing.
Right.
How is a person as somebody who's really tall going to wear this short.
You know it gives you really that kind of system without having to redesign and recut every time.
You literally just hit the nail on the head there.
Because there's so many body types.
It's like as much as we want to say like okay we've got you know a dozen presets.
You've got a thousand body types though.
So it is really cool to see how customizable that is.
Yeah.
Right.
It's I always thought that all these games that come out and they have your create your
own character.
Now you can do it all in Unreal.
And for this demo like super inspiring.
And I kind of want to make myself too.
All right.
Billy meet you.
Internal company challenge.
Here we go.
Okay.
Well I first of all I was just absolutely blown away and inspired by that.
So yes.
This is going to be a MetaHuman in my Clo future project files probably.
But our next one is a demo tutorial by me.
It is going to be all things about Clo.
And kind of really showing you how easy it is to get started.
Whether you are someone who has years of pattern making experience.
Or maybe somebody who has absolutely never made a garment in their entire life.
That is completely okay.
So Dan can you kick off my video please.
Hey everyone.
So we are going to jump right in with Clo 3D here.
Just a little bit about Clo 3D and what we are going to be doing today.
Everything that I am doing in Clo can also be done in our other program Marvelous Designer.
So when we think of Clo versus Marvelous Designer.
Clo is based for fashion and production in the real world.
Marvelous Designer is more of your 3D pipeline for gaming, VFX, special effects and animation.
And we are ready to start filling our space.
And we are going to be adding in from Unreal Engine our MetaHuman.
Which is going to be really easy and fast.
And if you have ever worked in Clo it is going to work really similar to that.
So when we are ready to bring in our avatar.
Which would have already been made in Unreal Engine's MetaHuman.
We are going to open up our Clo library.
Once we are in our Clo library.
This is going to be really similar to if we have ever opened up one of our Clo avatars.
For again Clo has a ton of different avatars.
I have a little folder handily ready for me.
Going to be bringing in Eta.
And I am going to go into my Eta folder.
And I am going to see I have again here is her little PNG.
And I need to bring in her body DNA.
Easy as a drag and drop.
From there I am going to also link in her head data.
As we you know kind of might want her head.
Give Clo a second. There we go.
And click OK.
Once that is done.
Clo is going to we can actually already see her added in behind.
Clo is just loading her in.
And once Eta is loaded in.
If I close my library.
There she is and I am ready to start dressing her.
Now that we have Eta our MetaHuman.
I am going to go back into our Clo library.
But this time instead of going into a folder I have already linked.
I am going to go into our Connect library.
So this guys this Connect store is you know maybe you are not a garment designer.
Maybe you have never made a real dress.
Before in your life.
This is a store full of tons of garments that you can use.
So I am going to go into our garment section.
And one extra thing.
I am going to turn on one of our filters.
And within our filters.
I am going to make sure I am going to be using some Connect official items.
So these are professionally made patterns.
And best part they are free.
I am going to head into our search box.
And I am going to type in for a running outfit.
And you can see once I type in running.
I get a ton of different outfits.
Or garments that are ready for me to use.
I can scroll through here as much as I want.
To see maybe what I would like to bring.
Bring into Clo.
And this running top is looking pretty cool for me.
So I am going to simply.
Actually I don't even need to right click guys.
All I need to do is double click.
And once I double click.
Clo is going to bring that garment in for me.
Making sure to add it.
Because I already have my avatar ready for me.
And I have the garment.
I can see the patterns in the 2D side.
I can see the garment in the 3D side.
Although seeing a little issue.
It is not quite fitting her.
This is where I can use the auto fit tool.
This is absolutely amazing.
I am going to use auto fit.
Using the default settings.
And pretty quick.
Clo is going to adjust the pattern.
Not only its sizing to fit the avatar.
But how she is positioned.
And it literally took two seconds.
Great.
I am going to bring in a pair of maybe some shorts.
For her to use.
Let me scroll through again.
And find a pair of shorts that I maybe want to use.
And here we go.
Here are some cute little shorts.
These look pretty good.
Double click to add.
Again I am not saving it as I am working.
Turning on the things I want to in the settings.
Clo is going to load those items in for me.
We have got some shorts.
Now again.
This time hey.
They didn't really end up right on her.
So I am going to use my little gizmo.
To move the shorts patterns around.
And also what is nice.
Is that I can jump over into my property editor.
And tell Clo that these shorts need to end up.
Underneath my existing shirt.
And I can turn on simulation.
And get these into position.
So that they are ready for me.
To start working.
Ah yes.
That worked much better.
And now I can put all of my garments back to layer zero.
So they aren't this neon green.
We can start to make any edits.
That we need to.
Looking at the pattern.
Well she has got some shorts.
And I am not really feeling the sleeves.
For this overall athletic outfit.
So I am going to simply select the sleeves.
And delete them.
They are gone.
Great.
And I think it might look cool.
If she has a little kangaroo pocket.
At the front of her shirt.
So I am going to go ahead.
And make some adjustments.
If you have ever worked in anything like.
Illustrator or anything.
The polygon tool is going to work.
Super similar to that.
And I can draw any type of shape.
That I might need to create.
Now that we have half of her pocket.
I can make any adjustments.
Maybe to the shape.
Make the opening maybe a little longer.
And make this maybe a little less wide.
Again I have only done half.
It is very easy to then just unfold it.
To create the full pocket shape.
And then trace this.
As an internal line.
Or internal shape.
Then be put.
Right onto the main pattern piece.
From there I am actually ready.
To sew everything into position.
Onto my garment.
Almost like in real life.
I am going to tell Chloe what to sew to what.
And in 3D.
We see those sewing lines up here.
And that pocket bag.
Snap into place.
And what I always think is really cool.
Is that we have a fully functioning pocket.
And I could put some stuff into it.
For later if I needed to.
Now that she has her pocket.
Maybe I want to make some further adjustments.
If I want to.
There is some really cool style line tools here.
That are actually let me make those adjustments.
In our 3D window.
I am going to go to my draw style line tool.
Select the garment that I want to make the adjustments to.
In this case her top.
And I want to draw.
New style line.
On the side panel.
Coming down the edge of her shirt.
What is really cool.
Is the moment I draw this line in the 3D window.
In the 2D window.
Chloe will actually cut apart.
And make a new pattern piece.
For that panel that I have just drawn.
Besides that I can even shorten and lengthen.
Different parts of the garment.
By using the move style line function.
Selecting let's say her collar.
And bringing that downward.
That is actually going to shorten.
Or reduce the overall height of her collar.
In just a click.
Now that I have shortened her collar.
I think for the rest of this athletic outfit.
She really could use.
Maybe a little zipper to the front.
The first thing though I need.
Is an area or portion of the pattern.
Where the zipper could actually go.
At the center front of her neck.
And for that a little bit of editing.
In our 2D window is needed.
I am going to add in a few extra points.
And that is going to let me start to drag down.
Areas of my pattern.
Let's zoom in a little more.
To create an overall area.
Where the zipper can go.
And what is nice is I can again look in the 3D window.
And in the 2D window at the exact same time.
That doesn't look quite big enough.
Or long enough.
That is looking a little better.
And using some alignment tools.
To make a nicer shaping for our zipper.
So I am going to align those.
To be nice and straight.
And same at the bottom.
I am going to align those points as well.
With the points being aligned.
So I now have a nice area.
To actually put in the zipper.
Taking my literally named zipper tool.
Adding a zipper to one side of my opening.
And then adding that exact same.
Link to the other side.
That is going to add in a zipper.
Into my paneling.
And Chloe is going to generate a zipper.
And once I turn simulation on.
Chloe is going to snap that zipper shut.
And we now have a zipper.
To the front of her jacket.
And I am excited as well.
I would like to actually go ahead.
And open up her zipper.
I can drag that zipper downwards in the 3D window.
Turning on simulation.
And we have now an unzipped zipper.
With her top done.
I want to start looking at maybe some of the things.
I could update on her shorts.
And I think like a cool contrast edge.
Of the bottom of the shorts.
Might look kind of fun.
Again jumping back over to my 2D side.
I can use my editing pattern tool.
And offset an internal line.
Of these pattern pieces.
For how wide I want my kind of.
Contrast piping to be.
Quarter of an inch I think is going to be pretty good.
Those internal lines.
Are going to automatically be selected.
And what is nice is.
With those internal lines selected.
I am going to cut and sew.
At the exact same time.
Cutting those away.
That contrast seam.
And eventually.
Contrast fabric.
The other thing I can do.
Is to add some additional thickness.
To these pattern pieces.
Either in the 2D or in the 3D window.
I have selected all four.
Of these little edge pieces.
And in my property editor.
I am going to come down to the additional thickness rendering.
And make that a little bit thicker.
So now it actually looks like.
Multiple layers of fabric.
Sewn together on our avatar.
It looks like our shirt is pretty good.
It looks like our shorts again are pretty good.
Now how about some fabrics.
Right now we are just using default fabric.
I am going to jump right back into my Clo library.
I am going to go into the default library.
The library comes with hundreds.
And hundreds of different fabrics.
For us to choose from.
And the best part is.
These are really easy to experiment and try out.
Pretty quick and easy.
I am just again going to start by.
Searching maybe a different fabric.
I am curious what would this look like.
If I did a leather.
So I am going to come in here.
And grab this animal alternative vegan leather.
Drag and drop it.
And completely start to replace.
Some of my different garments.
Again turning on simulation.
I can see how this is going to drape.
And be shaped differently.
Than it was in the default fabric.
So visually it is different.
And physically it is also different.
That is kind of an interesting choice.
Let's try something different.
Let's go with a chiffon.
I am going to actually experiment.
With these different fabrics.
So if I try these ones.
The garment is now.
It is a much lighter fabric.
But it is also completely see through.
Probably not the best for her running outfit.
Let's try something more likely being used.
Jersey.
Great I see a bunch of different jerseys.
That are available for me to use.
And I am going to again drag.
Drop and replace.
These different materials.
And again because simulation is turned on.
Those different changes being applied.
Perfect.
I think overall.
The jersey is looking pretty good.
Last shorts.
Alright I am thinking some sort of kind of like.
Swishy material.
So maybe I will go with a rip stop.
This time.
Got a couple of different rip stops.
Available to me.
I am going to go with a regular woven rip stop.
And instantly again.
Those shorts have changed their properties.
Their fit. They are already a bodycon short.
Not much of a difference.
But we can see here how these are starting to change.
How they visually look.
And then we can actually start to jump into color.
And how they are going to appear.
Because overall I am not loving the current color combo.
Let's just start with a completely white.
Outfit.
Way easier to work with something that is completely white.
Almost like a blank slate.
I have removed all of the colors.
From my different garments.
And now I can jump into my fabrics.
Let's go in to our shirt.
And I am going to go with.
Short first.
I am going to just go ahead and type in sky blue color.
Let's say.
And best part.
Quick and easy.
I can instantly see the change in the 2D and the 3D window.
This looks like a nice bright.
Happy blue.
Apply and close.
I am thinking maybe for the shorts.
We will keep the same overall color.
So again selecting the shorts material.
Luckily it leaves me right on that past.
Apply and close.
So I have got her overall.
Blue outfit.
I am thinking could use some maybe a little bit more fun.
Contrast colors.
Like that piping on the edge of her shorts.
Selecting the short.
Making a copy of the fabric with one click.
Changing that.
To what will be our combo color.
If we went with sky for the blue.
Maybe cloud.
For the contrast.
I now have a cloud version.
Of the same fabric.
And I will select my little edge pattern pieces.
And reassign it.
To the cloud combo rip stop.
Same with my top.
Maybe if I want to change a few of these upper areas.
As well.
I can select my jersey.
Create a copy of my jersey.
Change that color also to my now cloud color.
Select the pattern pieces.
That I want to be changed.
And simply reassign them.
I now have a newly color blocked outfit.
Ready to go.
So I am going to go ahead.
And I am going to go ahead.
And create a new material for my avatar.
Last but not least.
Maybe as well.
Adding in a graphic.
To add in a graphic.
You can add in png's or jpeg's.
Like a lot of other programs.
I have one ready for me to use here.
Just going to add in this cute little abstract sunset.
Add the graphic.
And click to place it.
Maybe adjust the size overall.
And now I can see.
Right on the back of my avatar.
graphic. Overall, I think we're done. Our MetaHuman is ready to be optimized before
getting sent back to Unreal. Thanks so much!
When preparing this outfit for Unreal, there are a few steps that you can do for optimization.
First, we can open the UV editor and adjust the UV shells for the patterns. What's nice
about Glow is that the UV shells are the exact same garment shapes created in the 2D layout,
so there's no need to manually cut UV seams or perform any unwrapping.
We can use the UV Packing dropdown and press Apply to pack all the UV shells we selected
into the 0 to 1 space.
To give our garment an extra detail pass, we can utilize the Everywhere tool to bake
a normal and ambient occlusion map. We can then send these texture maps over to Unreal
and add them to a material.
September 12 werd
Next.
Now we can export a garment as a USB. Go to File ExportUSD.
Make sure when exporting to select the Thick option and include Jiang Sun's garment simulation
data.
Mexico
Chicago
import the usd into unreal where unreal will import the skeleton and static meshes we need
hey and we're back and then so thank you also billy for adding to my video with your
definitely digital pipeline knowledge uh which i always appreciate yeah knowledge as well
yeah i i mean i've been a uh mostly marvelous user for a super long time and i'm always being
surprised by things that you can do uh because they're adding new features all the time and so
it was cool to see the style line tool that was it yeah so much like yeah super cool went bonkers
in my mind when i saw it for the first time and fun fact for the style line it was actually
designed our our founder of clow his name is jade and he actually designed it for his daughter who
didn't know how to make clothes so it's really cool to see like how
that tool evolved from like oh so my kid can make clothes now oh so people who maybe don't
do a lot of pattern making can make clothes super cool yeah i mean really seeing all these tools
where artists can just be artists right we don't have to go through like the long lengthy process
of getting there we can just dive right in um i just i'm amazed every time i see these tools advance
so finally our last video of the day today and this is kind of going to be like the piece
de resistance at the end of what we're going to be talking about today so we're going to be talking
about how that tool evolved from like oh so my kid can make clothes now oh so people who maybe don't
where you can actually put everything all together and this is going to be both kim and kami's
let's take clow let's take metahuman let's put them all into unreal so kim yeah the first part of this
video is going to be me showing you how to take the clothes back into unreal and make a resizable
outfit asset which is the thing that resizes with your metahuman um and then kami so i'm going to
actually then take you through what we've just launched on fab which is our metahuman fashion kit
which allows you to go ahead and bring your asset in put them into animation pre-created lighting
and actually go ahead and render it out so we kind of took those steps out
so you can actually just dive in like i said be an artist so um yeah let's take a look at it
so we're back in unreal after having made our garment and there's one last thing we
have to do before we create an outfit asset uh we're gonna go to metahuman character uh
export outfit body scale mesh and then we're gonna save that in our project and
what that's going to do is that's going to create a combined head and body mesh
for use with outfit assets and cloth assets and that's something we definitely need for an outfit
asset but the first thing that we have to do is we have to create something to put in there and
so we're going to create a cloth asset i'm going to right click in my content browser
and i'm going to go to physics cloth asset so that's going to create a new cloth asset for me so
at the time of this um usually you just double click but right now you should right click on
your cloth and go to open in data flow editor and you will get this which looks like a big old mess
um the good news is we basically don't want almost any of this so we can delete most of it only notes
that we really want to keep our usd import and transfer skin weights and the terraform though
so okay
to click over here and there's three dots in the usd file in the usd import node
and i'm going to select my usd
and look at that it brings in my garment now you're going to say that doesn't look quite right
um so we've got a couple of different views so if we look at render that should be what it is
that you're expecting uh right here on the top of the construction viewport um so there's
the render 3d sim 2d sim which shows you the pattern pieces that are all laid out
um and so that's how you import a ust
so back here inside of our cloth asset we're going to hook these nodes together so uh click
in here where this little dot is next to collection click and drag and drop it over here to collection
and now we're going to click on this transfer skin weights and so um when you click on a node
the properties show up over here and the thing that we're going to have to do is we're going
to have to if you remember we made that um combined skeletal mesh before so we have to click
in here to associate the body with the garment so now you can see it kind of shows up in this
closely fashion uh so now those two things are connected so uh and then
the last thing that we have to do is we have to connect this to the terminal node and this
is basically the most basic version of the clock asset that you need for the outfit asset
there's other things that you can do but you should definitely have these three nodes and
refer it to work properly and if you don't have any lots you can right click on here
and you can say remove option pin twice so now with these three nodes uh
including the body inside the transfer skin weights node we have what's the most
basic building blocks for an outside asset. So we can save it and we can move on to the outside asset.
There are a couple more sort of complex things like skinning maps
and logs that you can check out our documentation for.
Okay so here I have my cloth asset. I'm going to go up a directory
and I'm going to click in here, go to physics again, and this time I'm going to go to outside asset.
And this dialog box comes up and I want to choose resizable outfit. That's what we're
going to be using. Okay so now that I've selected that I can double click on my sporty outfit
and this comes up again. Looks kind of familiar. There's all this stuff in here
but we don't need to mess with any of that and all we need to do is over here on the side we
scroll down variable overrides and click a sized outfit source.
And this plus of how many sizes we have. Right now we only have the one size that we've created.
Sized meaning a garment that's made for a particular body. So if you made multiple
versions of the same garment associated with multiple bodies then you could put them in there.
And it's sort of resizing might be more accurate but as of right now we only have the one.
And so that's what we're putting in there. So this source asset is going to be my cloth asset.
So I'm going to click in there. There we go. I'm going to name it
size one. Doesn't really matter since we only have one size. Now I'm going to twirl this down and
over here is where I put in the body and this is going to be the same body that I put into my
transfer skin weights node. So I'm going to put in the body and this is going to be the same body that I put into my transfer skin weights node.
So I'm going to add that in and this is going to take a little while because right now
it's um it's cooking. It's pre-caching a whole bunch of stuff so it can be a lot
faster when it resizes. So I'm going to pause here.
Okay so I've made a new metahuman for us to test this new outfit asset on.
So I'm going to click over the hair and cloths that go down all the way to the
bottom to this area called outfit clothing. And so now I'm gonna find my outfit.
Uh the OA sporty outfit and I'm going to drag it right in here. That's going to create the wardrobe
item asset or WI and associated with your garment. The wardrobe item is an asset that travels alongside
your garment and can contain a lot of information that can be useful. So here's the wardrobe item.
I just double clicked on it um and here it is. So now it's already associated with the sporty outfit
since it got graded when I dragged it in. And I want to change this to metahuman. Metahuman.
Outfit pipeline. And so I'm going to twirl down pipeline and I'm going to change this right here
from editor pipeline to metahuman outfit editor pipeline. And if you don't want to do anything else
that's all of all you need to do. But there are a couple other things that you might find
interesting in the wardrobe item. So one of the really valuable things to show you is um I'm going to twirl the editor pipeline outfit.
And body hidden face map texture. And so here you can create a texture. And so I'm going to just
briefly show you what I've made. And so this is the texture that's based on the UVs of the body.
White says keep and black says remove. And so it removes all of the faces
underneath the garment that you paint out that you can designate.
And what that does is that not only makes your metahuman lighter but it also can
eliminate some of the issues with clipping that sometimes happens both with resizing and with
deformation when your character starts moving. So I'm just going to minimize this. And I'm going to
see in my sporty asset I'm going to drag in that file. So that's just like a ping file.
Um it'll get imported as a texture. And it's called sporty clothes body mask. And so now
when I go back to my wardrobe item I can put that in there.
Sporty clothes body mask.
And so now what that's going to do is that is going to
remove all of the faces that I decided I didn't want to show. So I'm going to save this.
And then now I'm going to go back to my test character. And now I can put the clothing on the
character. And so this is just the default shape. And it's going to resize from Etta's shape to
the shape of this body. And so if we go into body. And we you know let's see let's just play
around with some sliders. The garment will resize to the character.
So now that I've tested my garment and I feel satisfied with how it's working I'm going to
publish it. And so I go to here window metahuman manager.
Which brings up metahuman manager which can detect all of the outfit assets that I have in my
project. And so I'm going to verify. It's going to tell me that I have a couple warnings but
nothing read so it passes. And so the verification tests are just a bunch of tests um that make sure
that your garment is going to work properly when you send it along to you know so everyone can be
sure that things are going to work properly. So then I'm going to click package.
That's just going to bring up a dialog box that's going to have me type in the file name and choose
where it goes. And then it will package it up into a mh package m-h-e-k-g. If you package up
your asset in this way uh it will if you upload it to fab it will go on to the metahuman channel
which is a channel that has um all metahuman assets that have been verified just like yours
mh packages are also a great way to share your asset with your friends and colleagues.
I'm going to send mine to Kami right now and she's going to take over.
Hi I hope you're enjoying the demo. My name is Kami and I'm here to show you how to
take the clothing back into unreal and metahuman creator and add it to your project.
From there we'll go ahead and replace your character in this scene
that's already set up. This is actually a project that is available now on fab. It's the metahuman
kit. It comes with several different animations for you to use and lighting setups, sequencer setups,
just you know all around to get you going really fast to see what your new clothing looks like.
All right let's get started. So I've gone ahead and already created a clothing directory.
I'm just going to drag and drop the package that Kim and Chloe gave to me. Otherwise you can also
hit import here if you'd like to but it pretty much just does the exact same thing. It's just
bringing it in running it and then you can just drag and drop the package and it's ready to go.
So I'm going to go ahead and create a new clothing directory. I'm going to go ahead and
get through a process to see if it meets validation and pretty soon a window is going to
pop up and let us know if the clothing worked. There it is right on cue. Once the clothing comes
in you can go ahead and reopen metahuman creator and from there we're just going to go and like Kim
showed for the hair and clothing section and we're going to go down and grab the metahuman wardrobe item.
And drop it right in. You need to click on it and then go ahead and hit where and it will apply it to
your character. It usually doesn't take too long to get on there and boom there we go.
All right from there you just need to go ahead and hit assemble
and basically one thing to remember is you don't actually have to create the rig again.
It's already gone through that process and the clothing is attached and it just comes with it for
free.
In here the other thing to look at is exactly what type you want, the highest quality,
you can put this in, and then the naming. Whatever this name is here is what it will be in your
editor and if you already have an asset named that it will write over that. You can just change the
name here to write out as a different asset. Once you've done that you just go ahead and hit
assemble and then from there you should be good to take a look at the character.
As you can see though in here I do have a pre-assembled character. I wanted to go ahead
and do this so I can show you a feature of MetaHuman Creator which is that you can preview
your animation in your outfit. I'm going to move it to the body realm. I'm going to actually hit play
and there we go. It's now moving around which is really great to like kind of see how your clothes
can form and move with the character and all of that. I'm going to hit save and then I'm going to
go ahead and add a new background with a background. I don't know how to do this on a
video but this would be really cool. I'm just going to skip all the
regular ways that it does. You can also so you know add a specific animation. If you have
something already ready to go, you can put it in there and give that a try.
I'm going to close this. Okay so now let's go ahead and come back to our sequencer and add our
character in. Let's go to the front camera. I'll show you how to change that. This is our sequencer
and because you're going to have to go ahead and set up the camera for the show. I'm going to show
sequencer and you can actually change between cameras by right-clicking and
selecting another one that is existing in your level sequence so we're gonna go
to the front camera and let's go ahead and add our character the one with
clothing on it and you just drop it in kind of whenever or wherever I usually
like to go and immediately set the LOD sync to zero so that I it always stays
at the highest fidelity and there just go back to sequencer right click assign
actor and switch it to your other character and boom they've switched
spots so you're the characters still there you can delete them or you can
come over into the outliner and type in hidden in game and they will just go
ahead and hide so this is our kit what you're looking at right now is one of
our catwalk and
animations and there are several other level sequences already ready to go
idle and a walk and just some poses and yeah it can pretty much just cycle
through that I'm gonna go ahead and pause it here I'm going to show you that
you can also switch up lighting it's just muting and unmuting right here and
it gives you just a different look work with all right so that is basically how
you switch it into one of our current sequences
you can go ahead and add your character and switch it into one of our current sequences
that we provide let's go ahead and take a look at switching it out or and
putting it into a new sequence and a new level I'm just gonna go to the content
browser I'm just gonna select levels we'll do it here file new level let's
just go ahead and do an empty one because we're gonna use a lighting
sequence that's already available to us I'm not gonna save that for right now I'm gonna save that for right now
let's go ahead and create a level sequence okay let's open up the studio
let's right click add a sub sequence track I'm here we're gonna go ahead and
select I knew I wanted to put in my studio lighting there are three presets
in here that you can grab let's just do that one
right there and there you go as you can see it's kind of set up a dome with some
lighting in it. It's going to give us a good studio setup. Let's go ahead and add
our metahuman in there. Drag and drop. Do the things. Quality sync to 0. And then let's go back up here and
zero it out. Hit G to hide everything and just kind of go take, you know, a look at the
character. All right, let's line this up here. Let's focus on it. There we go. Okay, so let's go ahead and
put some animation on this character. I'm going to take it from here, drop it into the sequencer. The
animation tabs are going to open up with a control rig. We are not going to use that for this demo.
Let's go ahead and delete those. If you do not delete them and you add animation, you will not see your
animation. All right, we'll
click on body, the plus sign, animation. I know I want to use idle for the body. And then there's also
the face. Animation, face, and when you look at that and hover over, you'll see it's 649 frames. There you
need to go and adjust your timeline to be 649. Anything that you want to be persistent throughout the
whole timeline, go ahead and adjust those to be 649 as well.
And then also, I know this lighting, we're going to go ahead and want to loop so that it'll just stay on the whole time.
And there we go. We now have a level sequence with some anim. All we're missing is camera. Let's go ahead and set that up.
I'm liking this positioning here, so I'm going to go ahead and hit the camera button. It moves in a little bit, but as you can see, I'm piloting it.
So I'm just going to zoom out a little.
And there we go.
I think I like that.
I'm going to go ahead and adjust the details on it for the focus, because the focus likes to set itself to manual and some things will be out.
I'm going to disable that for now.
All right.
And we now have cameras.
There we go.
I was going to say I picked up the wrong one.
We are good to go for camera.
And yeah, that is pretty much how you can set up your character and get it ready to go.
If you wanted to at this point, you could go ahead and render.
We're in the sequence.
You're going to hit Movie Render Queue.
And from here, in this particular project, I have two presets from Movie Render Graph that will go ahead and give you either JPEGs or an MP4.
There's also the defaults, and you can create your own.
Just click on that.
And from there, you would hit Render.
I'm not going to do that right now because it would take a couple minutes.
But yeah, have a look and give it a try.
All right.
I'm going to close that.
Okay.
Let's go ahead and see one next thing I think I want to do.
Let's go ahead and I'm going to delete the animation from here.
I am going to stop highlighting my camera.
I'm going to zoom in on the face here.
I want to add a light and a highlight to the eyes.
I think will really help set her up.
Really nicely.
Okay.
So I've done that.
I'm going to actually create another camera.
And like I said, I went ahead and did the focus.
So we're going to go ahead and change that back to disable.
All right.
And then I'm going to go ahead and I think we're good here.
But I want to go ahead and, like I said, get a highlight in her eyes.
So to do so, I'm going to go and put it into a double window.
I'm going to click on the asset on the left side and hit Focus.
I'm close to her.
I'm back over here to clear out the extra gameplay stuff.
So this is my camera that we were just looking in.
And now what I'm going to go ahead and do is drop a light in.
Let's do this spotlight.
Oh, there it is.
It went ahead.
Let's just put it at neutral and click on it again.
And I'm going to hit Control Shift P.
And I'm now piloting the light.
So the reason I want to do this is it allows me to easily move the light around and get it into...
Nice.
So as you can see, I'm getting really close.
But that's because I just really want to see what's going on.
Now I'm going to back out.
I'm going to go a little to the left and down a little and back out a little bit more.
All right.
Now I'm going to come over.
Let's see.
I'm going to turn a little bit more.
Okay.
If I come over here, I can now see this really tiny glint.
And also her face is kind of lit up too much.
So I'm going to drop the light down.
Now the glint has gotten kind of small and gone away.
So we need to go ahead and kick up the radius.
And now you see.
Kind of coming back in.
We've now got this nice highlight in her eyes that wasn't there before.
Really, really subtle.
But it just kind of pulls her in.
And, you know, makes her look good and like she's really sitting in the scene.
And that is pretty much it for setting up lighting and animation in the project.
All right.
Now it's time to have some fun.
Let's bring your MetaHuman to life.
So click over to the Live Link tab.
We're going to go ahead and add our camera.
We're going to choose Logitech Brio because it runs at a higher FPS.
The higher the FPS, the better.
So from here, we're going to go ahead and type the subject name in.
It can really be whatever you want.
You just have to connect it to your asset.
So there we go.
And click on that.
Let's get rid of the fuzz.
And...
Hi.
You're live.
What?
Okay.
Let's make one last adjustment.
Look forward.
Right above the top of your camera.
Neutral face.
There we go.
My lips.
Eyes.
And head move a lot more accurately with mine.
So does my body.
Fun, right?
Now your turn.
Go play.
Thanks.
Bye.
Oh.
Are you still here?
Okay.
I'll come see you in a minute.
Bye.
Please stop.
I thank you.
Bye.
Love this game so much.
Have fun playing Mimei.
Bye.
cool i forgot we were talking to a metahuman i thought like i thought i was a real person at
the end you know if you told me i mean i totally should come back is that right yeah 100% we're
talking about that it was i'll come back as metahuman versions of ourselves and then we're
good right you like the ultimate turing test can can you tell that we switched ourselves out
can you tell guys can you tell or i probably like give myself bright pink hair or something
you know what's actually really interesting is you can tell all the little inflections when you
switch people it's just the little subtleties that make them them just come through um especially
being able to do it real time just from a web camera like yeah i couldn't you'd see your face
driving mine which would be really weird it's just that that would be a fun game almost like
guess who is the person behind the metahuman exactly exactly okay that would actually be
absolutely so okay game game night guys we're gonna do this we can try on different clothing
we can dance through it you know
you
got this who's the imposter you know oh oh god okay there we go i mean hey why not i'd love to
see if people actually play this we could start a new trend all right guys so first i hope everybody
enjoyed all of these different videos i know i really love watching them personally actually so
that i always think that's really cool because i know i just learned a whole bunch of stuff that i
did not know beforehand um but it is time to open up our q a and keep in mind the chat is open so
if you thought of any questions
don't just type them in we've got people watching the chat which is always really cool
and i'm going to just kind of kick it off with one of our first ones and someone asked which
program is better to learn marvelous designer or clout and honestly that's a question that's it's
a great question and i could almost say both it really depends on what your actual output
is are you looking to print your patterns and make a dress in real life for a shirt or a
suit i mean the world is your oyster you can make a handbag a backpack so many things but if you want
to make it in the real world, I would definitely recommend Clo. But if your output is going to be
more about a digital pipeline, dressing characters, creating animations, video games, special effects,
then that is going to be Marvelous Designer and using that. So it is really cool to see that. But
the nice thing is the programs are very similar. The interfaces look very similar. In fact,
you could probably jump from one to the other and back again. There's just a few tools that
are different. You're going to have things like seam allowance in Clo, because you kind of need
seam allowance to sew things together. You have the render engine in Clo to render, because mostly
in Marvelous Designer, people are often taking it into the next step, the next program. Billy,
are there any other fun things you can add or that might be differences of Clo and MD?
Well, I was just going to add that we are probably 75% the same framework, but it's that additional
work that we're working on right now. So it's going to be a little bit different, but it's going to
be a little bit different, but it's going to be a little bit different, but it's going to be a little
bit different. So we have a little 25% that leans towards fashion-based tools, right? And then we
have the other 25% for Marvelous, which is more VFX and game-oriented tools. So we have like the,
I would say what sets us apart is like everywhere. We have different Kinect store assets as well.
So yeah. I mean, I've been using Marvelous for years and literally just this week, I
hopped into Clo to try and mess around and make something and found it pretty much fine. You know,
things are in a slightly different place, but if you know how to use one, it feels like you know
pretty well how to use the other. I'm excited. Kim's going to be joining us for a workshop and
it's going to be really cool to see her jump from Marvelous Designer into Clo. I'm kind of excited.
All right. So our next question, why does my MetaHuman have only two slots for clothing? Well,
almost all the YouTube tutorials have four. I can only change the whole body,
mesh or the face, no shirt, pants, or shoes. So the answer to this is that there are no specific
slots as of right now for clothing. You can put on as many pieces of clothing as you want,
but there are no specific slots. So we kind of left it open to keep it sort of infinite just
because it's really hard to define a lot of those, you know, slots and figuring out all of the rules
and stuff. But if you want to put on shirt and pants and shoes, like just put them on, just,
you can double click on them to take, to put them on.
Double click on it to take them off and put on as many things as you want. Like you can be like
Joey from Friends if you want. So like the reference, I mean, come on layer, put it all on,
put it all on all of it. I mean, did you have anything to add or. No, I mean, it's just one
of those things, you know, playing with the tool. You can't actually do exactly that layer close up
as I was testing it out. I realized that I kept putting things on to wear and then I had to go
back through and I was like, oh, you can just click on it and tell it to.
To not, it's really actually pretty easy to use. And yeah, like I said, Joey's a good reference.
Not going to get that image out of my head for a while now. Yeah. I mean, it's a little different
because everything else, if you click on, if you apply something like a groom, for instance,
then the other one will turn off automatically. And with clothing, it doesn't work with that
because we want to enable you to put on as many things as you want to. So it doesn't switch. You
have to take things off if you want to take them off as much as you want. All right, next. Can you
customize the hair too, or is it just those options? So I'm not exactly sure what those
options are. I'm guessing it's the stuff that I showed from Fab. You can customize that. I mean,
so you can download grooms off of Fab. You know, we have some from Epic. There's also like a ton
of user created ones. You can also create them and there's actually a bunch of, I mean, there's
like a few, I forget the exact name of them, but like groom starter kits, I think they're called on
there. And they, there's a bunch of tools and stuff that Epic has made to make it easier for
you to create your own grooms, which are really cool. We're not going to discuss them here, but
you should definitely look into it because they are very cool. And then you can just put them
right onto your MetaHuman once you're done. Yeah. I mean, the main one is the Maya to
Houdini plugin that works really well for designing it. There's a lot of great tutorials that recently
came out from, I believe we launched it last Unreal Fest and, you know, a lot of people have
been able to really just kind of dive in. So definitely check out online. You'll be able to
find the tutorials you need to get you through this. I want to jump to another hair related
question. So we keep those together, but can you bring the hair into Clo3D that you picked
for your MetaHuman? And currently not yet, but as many things say, the key word there is yet,
because you never know what's coming down the pipeline.
And then.
Next question. Can we use this auto size adjusting thing with every piece of clothing
and every avatar? Why did she not use it to fit the pants? Why did I? So auto fit.
Key really with that right now is that it works with one garment at a time. So if I had had the
top or had no top and just the pants, I could have fit that one at the same time. It's really
just knowing which one. So I would, you know, if I wanted to do both, I do the top, save that garment,
do the pants, save that garment, and then bring them together into one file. So for now it's just
the one. But in the future, again, not yet, but this tool got is getting better and better and
better. In fact, the way that it just hopped onto how the unreal or the MetaHuman's arms were
absolutely blew me away because if you tested this tool years ago, it wouldn't have worked
as flawlessly. And now it was like, perfect done. Whoa, blew me away. And the other thing is,
can you use this on other avatars? Can you use this on other avatars? Can you use this on other avatars?
100%. There is a funny video, I believe it's somewhere on our YouTube, and it has it
addressed. It starts on an avatar, a clo avatar, then it goes on to a little kid avatar,
and then it goes on to, I think, Sting from Spider-Man, and then it goes on to a horse.
So yes, it can go on to a lot of different characters. So, you know, I never thought I'd
see a horse in clo, but yes, you can dress a horse in clo and you can put a dress on it.
That was previously on a normal avatar. So it's kind of fun to see that you can definitely
expand on those options. Yeah. And it's
actually a thing to point out. We didn't really go into it with the outfit asset,
but the outfit asset can accept sort of multiple size sources. And so auto-fitting is like a really,
really easy way to make multiple sizes. And then when you bring the outfit asset in,
it sort of makes the resizing more accurate if you have more sources. So it's a cool thing to know.
Lily, just totally curious, have you ever put a garment onto a not human avatar?
Like I did this like toon kind of creature, like goblin recently.
It was, but like, luckily it was pretty humanoid, but it is definitely interesting
because we have examples, like you said, of the horse. And also something that we have that
people may not know is that we have baby avatars in both softwares. So you can do like really,
like tiny outfits and with the auto scaling tool, you can put that outfit onto a larger person as
well.
Just to point out, there are no babies in metahuman or kids. But yeah.
Yeah. I think one of our baby names is baby juju. And with the labubu craze last year,
I dressed up baby juju like a labubu. Yeah. So, you know, the, the imagination,
you're only limited by your own imagination. You can do all sorts of crazy stuff.
All right, this next question did kind of get answered,
but I'll bring it up in case they want to speak
a little bit more about it, is can you
export your MetaHuman in Clo back to Unreal Engine
to make an animation there?
In Clothes?
In Clo, I think they meant Clo.
You guys, you were.
I mean, so I think Kami pretty much answered this question
with her video.
Yes.
Yes, you can.
Yeah, but I also love that sometimes people ask questions
and you're like, clearly we're moving in the right direction
because we're about to answer it.
We're about to answer it, yeah.
Yeah, and I think we put a link in the stream about where
the fashion kit is.
So if you want, you can go ahead and use the example
that we just showed you today and create your own.
All right, our next question.
Is the USD to Unreal Engine still the optimal workflow
that exports thin and thick version clothing for Unreal
Engine to simulate?
And does the new Marvelous Designer optimized quad topology
support this workflow?
So I'm going to answer the first part of this question.
Yeah, yes, it is.
I mean, if you want both the sim mesh and the render mesh,
which is the thin and the thick, you definitely
want to use a USD because that just brings them both in.
That brings in a lot of really cool information.
Like, it has the flattened pattern pieces.
It has the 3D representation, both in the sim mesh,
the thin and the thick.
So yeah, you get a ton of really great information, sewing
information, et cetera, with the USD import.
But I'm going to assume it supports the optimized
the quad topology.
I don't know, Billy or Ariel?
Yeah, so it definitely does.
And my recommendation for why switching to quads
is just because if you're going to animate that clothing later
on, you should be able you should
be getting more predictable results based with the quad
mesh rather than triangles.
It is good to point out that once it comes into UE,
it will get triangulated.
Anyway, but it still might be more predictable topology.
So always good.
All right, our next question, is it
possible to add chaos cloth dynamics to parametric outfit?
It seems as a very logical pipeline to have.
I agree.
That does seem like a very logical pipeline to have.
And it's something that we are very interested in doing.
But like Ariel was saying before, not yet.
I don't know if that's a favorite word.
Yeah, yes, I agree.
It would be really awesome.
All right, so our next question.
For game devs who already have lots of assets with clothing,
is there a workflow to import regular mesh clothes
and turn them into metahuman clothing?
I'm not exactly sure.
I'm not sure when you're saying lots of assets with clothing,
is there a workflow?
Is there a workflow to import regular mesh clothes
and turn them into metahuman clothing?
I mean, there's definitely the workflow that we just showed
is the workflow to import regular mesh clothes
and turn them into, I'm assuming you're
talking about an outfit asset.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
This question is a little unclear.
But yeah, if you already have existing metahuman skeletal
assets, then that you can definitely do to turn into,
an outfit asset, if maybe that's what you're asking.
And you just basically would take those meshes out
of your skeletal asset and sort of use them as static meshes
and then just do the pipeline that I showed as normal.
And then those will turn into resizable outfit assets.
I always keep on remembering both Chloe and Epic
have forums to definitely ask lots and lots of your questions
because we might not be able to answer all of them.
Yeah.
But we'll get to them today.
All right.
Our next one, how do we deal with LODs
when it comes to clothing for the metahuman?
OK.
So there is a workflow.
I just didn't have time to show it.
You can create LODs in your original, in your cloth asset.
There's just a couple of nodes that you would add.
I can't really show it right now.
And I'm blanking on the name of the node right now.
But it basically.
It really remeshes your clothing.
And you just choose, essentially, a percentage
of how many faces you want it to do.
And it will just automatically LOD them for you,
which is super cool.
And last, I think, or I think this might be our last question.
But so if you have any last minute ones,
make sure you put them in the chat.
But can parametric outfits have chaos cloth dynamics?
Oh, we answered this question.
Oh, I literally, wow.
I read it and then I read it again.
Wow.
Next one, how to stop, this is what
happens when you do things live, guys.
It's live.
It's really, we are right here.
So how to stop clipping of complex clothing like jackets.
OK, so I guess that you're asking about how
to stop the clipping in between, let's say,
a shirt and a jacket, or a jacket and a pant or a skirt,
anything like that.
Currently, right now, we don't have ways to sort of move
things out, move things in.
Tuck them.
Tuck them, et cetera.
Right now, it just is kind of you get what you get.
And so the way that you would do this
is you would create assets that go together.
Obviously, in the future, it's something
we'd love to also address.
But right now, that's just what you do.
And in resizing, obviously, and in allotting,
certainly, if you go down to a lower resolution,
sometimes clipping can appear where there might not
have been clipping.
One of the settings, I don't remember
if I addressed this or not, in Outfit Asset,
sort of the last setting is a number of something points,
interpolation points.
And if you turn that up in your Outfit Asset,
you'll get a more, like, sort of more fidelity in the resizing.
And it'll really stick to the body more,
which can be both good or bad.
But that's something you might want
to play with if everything looks fine,
and then when you resize it, it doesn't look fine.
But in general, right now, the big answer there is, just,
create assets that work together, and find us in the future.
Oh, my god, guys.
So I think we had a lot of really great questions.
I appreciate them.
Keep in mind Epic, Clo, Marvelous Designer.
We've got forums, great places.
We've got Discord channels, guys.
We've got places that you can go to ask your questions
for more, longer, in-depth answers, and possibly,
you know, step-by-step instructions.
So it was super exciting to have you
guys all here.
I am so excited.
I hope we get the chance to do something like this again
in the future.
It's been an absolute treat for myself.
I'll let anyone else have any last minute things they want to say,
or just a quick thank you.
No?
Thanks, everyone.
Yeah.
All right, guys.
Yeah, guys.
So again, thank you all so much.
I hope you enjoyed this.
Don't keep in mind, there will be a blog post later
from Epic, Clo, and Marvelous Designer that you will,
there will be lots of links with resources,
and as well as this stream.
So you will be able to watch it later, if you like.
Yeah.
If you're like, oh my god, I really
want to go back and watch that one part again,
you'll be able to do that.
And we will see you later.
Thank you guys so much.
Bye.